Weatherwax mss., 1915-1975 LMC 2283
Lilly Library
Weatherwax mss.
1915-1975
Lilly Library
Weatherwax, Paul, 1888-
LMC 2283
6 Boxes
The Weatherwax mss., 1915-1975, consists of the papers of botanist Paul Weatherwax, 1888-1976.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1977
Biographical Note
Paul Weatherwax, 1888-1976, was an American botanist and an IU faculty member. A native of Worthington, Indiana, Weatherwax attended both Wabash College and DePauw University in 1909 and 1910 respectively, but received his A.B., magna cum laude, from Indiana University in 1914. He then continued in graduate work at IU, receiving his MA in 1915 and PhD in 1918. Weatherwax first joined the IU faculty as an instructor while doing graduate work, moved to the University of Georgia as an associate professor after completing his degree, and returned to Indiana University in 1921 where he stayed until retirement in 1959. He remained a very active Professor Emeritus on the Bloomington campus until his death in 1976.
Weatherwax authored several books, including The Story of the Maize Plant (1923), Elementary Botany (1942), and Indian Corn in Old America (1954), as well as numerous articles for both scientific and historical publications. He was also the author of the IU walking guide called The Woodland Campus of Indiana University (1966). Weatherwax's major areas of research were the morphology of grasses, and the morphology, origin, and history of the Indian corn plant. Among the many awards he received were the Waterman Fellowship, 1925-1930, and a traveling Guggenheim fellowship, 1944-1945. Prior to retirement Dr. Weatherwax headed the teaching group of Indiana University faculty in Bangkok, Thailand, on a Science Education contract with that country, 1957-1959.
Scope and Content Note
This collection includes correspondence, writings, photographs, college class notes, seed lists, trip diaries, and materials relating to Indiana University faculty activities.
The Correspondence and Subject Files have been retained as Weatherwax arranged them, including folder headings. Consequently, they contain such diverse material as photographs, clippings, botany course outlines, insurance policies, faculty meeting reports, correspondence with botanists, publishers, and seed companies, galley proofs, etc. Writings by Paul Weatherwax include his incomplete manuscript for "The Morphology of Grasses." The Miscellaneous section includes college class notes, seed accession lists, trip diaries, and materials relating to Indiana University faculty activities. The collection has been partially indexed. An inventory and list of index entries is available.
Arrangement/Organization
The collection is organized into the following series: I. Correspondence and Subject Files; II. Writings; III. Miscellaneous.
Botany.; Botanists --Correspondence.; Corn --History.; Grasses.; Trees --Identification.; Indiana University; Science; Indiana University; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of Plant Sciences; Weatherwax, Paul, 1888- --Correspondence.; Weatherwax, Paul, 1888-. Woodland campus of Indiana University.; Deam, Charles Clemon, 1865-1953
- Correspondence and subject files, A-Z., 1915-1975 (Box 1-4)
  - In the correspondence are letters of: (Box 1-4)
    General
    Avery, George Sherman, 1903-
    Breneman, William Raymond, 1907-
    Burnham, Charles Russel, 1904-
    Camp, Wendell Holmes, 1904-1963
    Carter, George Francis, 1912-
    Davis, Bradley Moore, 1871-1957
    Douglass, Benjamin Wallace, 1882-1939
    Emerson, Rollins Adams, 1873-1947
    Evans, Arthur Thompson, 1888-1943
    Friesner, Ray Clarence, 1894-1952
    Gates, Reginald Ruggles, 1882-1962
    Gershoy, Alexander, 1896-
    Girton, Raymond Elvood, 1899-
    Goddard, David R., 1908-
    Goldsmith, William Marion, 1888-1955
    Griggs, Robert Fiske, 1881-
    Hackel, Eduard, 1850-1926
    Hall, Ford Poulton, 1898-1951
    Harper, Earl Enyeart, 1895-1967
    Hatt, Robert Torrens, 1902-
    Hayward, Herman Eliot, 1892-
    Henderson, Norlan Clarence, 1915-
    Hitchcock, Charles Leo, 1902-
    Hoar, Carl Sherman, 1889-
    Howard, Louis Bradley, 1905-
    Huxley, Julian Sorell, 1887-1975
    Iltis, Hugo, 1882-1952
    Jones, Volney Hurt, 1903-
    Loehwing, Walter Ferdinand, 1896-1960
    Lonnquist, John Hall, 1916-
    McMullen, Lynn Banks, 1875-1963
    McNutt, Paul Vories, 1891-1955
    Martin, Paul Sidney, 1898-
    Melhus, Irving E., 1881-
    Neumann, George Karl, 1907-1971
    Palmquist, Edward Marshall, 1917-
    Polunin, Nicholas, 1909-
    Postelthwait, Samuel Noel, 1918-
    Prat, Henri Charles, 1902-
    Rainaley, Francis, 1870-1942
    Raines, Richard Campbell, 1898-
    Rogers, John Sinclair, 1917-
    Rutledge, Wiley, 1894-1949
    Stadler, Lewis John, 1896-1954
    Stanfield, Joseph Fisher, 1901-1958
    Taylor, William Randolph, 1895-
    Tomes, Mark Louis, 1917-
    VanFleete, Dick Scott, 1912-
    Visher, Stephen Sargent, 1887-1967
    Wailer, Adolph Edward, 1892-
    Whaley, William Gordon, 1914-
    Whistler, Roy Lester, 1912-
    Wiley, Richard Haven, 1913-
    Williams, Oscar Brown, 1895-1959
    Wilson, Carl Louis, 1897-
    Winchester, Albert McCombs, 1908-
  - A-E, (65 folders)
    - A., 1930-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Academy of Sciences - Historical., 1936-1973; Includes photos, programs, etc. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Acme Agency., 1942-1944; Correspondence about translating P.W.'s book on maize (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Book Co., 1945-1950; About reviewing of texts of A.B.C. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Heritage., About request for use of an illustration. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Anderson, E.G., 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Anderson, Edgar., 1941-1957; About specimens. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Andronescu, D.I., 1917-1923 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Anthropological., 1934-1952; About Indian corn hills, etc. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Arber, Agnes., 1925-1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Australia - Botanical Gardens Experiment Stations., 1918-1962; About grasses. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Autographs., 1921-1947; includes necrology of I.A.S.; speaking invitations; photographs. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - B., 1935-1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Barro Colorado Island., 1945-1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Black, Glenn A. & Bushnell, T.M., 1937-1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Blom, Frans., 1935-1957; About publications. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Book Dealers., 1918-1957; About buying & selling of (rare) books. (Box 1, Folder 17)
      See also: Weigel, Oswald
    - Book Reviews., 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Botanical Society of America - Inactive File., 1938-1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Botany in Indiana., 1950-1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Botany 101, 102., 1942-1951; Includes articles, etc. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Brand, Donald D., 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Briscoe, Herman T., 1942-1949 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Brodie, Harold J., 1956-1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Brown, Mr. & Mrs. V.E., 1937-1944; Includes sale lists of plants. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Brussels Botanical Garden., 1935-1969; About seeds. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bryan, William Lowe., 1927-1946; About Indiana University business. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Buitenzorg., 1916-1923; About corn seeds. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - C., 1921-1955 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Campus Trees Booklet., 1960-1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Campus Trees - Labeling., 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
    - Campus Trees - Supplementary Materials., 1940-1954; Printed material includes articles; maps, guides; etc. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Carter, Floyd., 1929-1949; About seed collections. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Castetter, Edward F., 1937-1953 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Chase, Agnes., 1923-1957; About Smithsonian Institute correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - China & Chinese., 1921-1930; About etymology of Chinese word for corn. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Chronica Botanica., 1939-1955; Includes catalogs, pamphlets. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Church - Methodist., 1941-1969; About church business, etc. (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Cleland, Robert E., 1938-1963 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Collins, J.L. & Kempton, J.H., 1917-1952; About seeds. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Commercial., 1925-1933; Includes: National Cob Pipe Works; Grains of "cob" corn; Eli Lilly: pernicious anemia: corn grown commercially. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Conservation, U.S. Dept. of., 1927-1973 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Corn (book) - Reviews., 1954-1973 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Corn Problems - Queries and Comments., 1952-1973 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Corn - Questions., 1920-1932 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Cornell University - Agricultural Experiment Station., 1919-1934 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Cosgrove, Mary (University of Illinois)., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Courses - Outlines., Includes a number of printed outlines of Botany Courses. (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Courses - Proposed - Indiana University., 1937; Includes 4 proposals. (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Cruxent, Jose M., 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Cutler, Hugh C., 1944-1950; About corn; grasses. (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - D., 1921-1970 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Deam biography. (Box 1, Folder 54-56)
      See also: Writings in Box 5.
    - DeVol, Charles E., 1931-1974; About specimens. (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Discussion Club., 1928-1974; Includes notes, roster, & programs. (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Dobbins, David., 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Duncan, Wilbur H., 1934-1952; About specimens. (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - E., 1919-1951 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Eames & McDaniels - PLANT ANATOMY, McGraw-Hill., 1940; About revisions. (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Elias, Maxim K., 1942-1947 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Encyclopedias., 1953-1968; About research on articles on grasses & corn. (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Evans, Morgan W., 1923-1933; About herbs & seeds. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - F-J, 56 Folders
    - F., 1943-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Faculty - Annual Reports., 1947-1957 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
    - Faculty Committees - Policy., 1943-1951 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Committees - Policy - Curriculum., 1945-1948 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
    - Faculty Committees - Post War Planning., 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Faculty Committees - Rules & Business., 1946-1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Faculty Committees - Survey Committee., 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Faculty Council., 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Field Course., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Florida Agricultural Experiment Station., 1917-1933 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Franklin College., 1960-1974; Includes reports, pamphlets, programs, etc. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Funk Brothers., 1944-1961; Includes pamphlets, etc. about corn. (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
    - Funk Brothers - The Great Story of Corn., 1953-1961; Includes shooting script; comments, etc. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - G., 1918-1957 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Genetics Society., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Graduate Students. Dr. Lois Farquharson., 1952-1961 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Graduate Students. Elfrieda Lang., 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Graduate Students. Cecilia Josephine Lauby., 1948 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Graduate Students. H. Bruce Ledin., 1940-1950 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Graduate Students. Scott McCoy., 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Graduate Students. Barbara Peebles., 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Graduate Students. Y.F. Shen., 1949-1954 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Graduate Students. Bertice Clarence Williams., 1945-1948 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Grants., 1931-1932; Includes proposals. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Grasses, Miscellaneous., 1961-1970 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Guatemala., 1932-1945 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation., 1944-1962; Includes applications, bibliographies, etc. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - H., 1925-1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Hanover College., 1962-1966; Includes syllabi, grades, etc. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Harcourt, Brace & Co., 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Harshberger, John W., 1917-1928 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Hayes, Lois F., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Heinesch, Arthur., 1915-1929 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Historic Preservation., 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Hitchcock, A.S. - U.S.D.A., 1917-1933 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Hunt Botanical Library., 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Hybrid Corn., 1939-1957 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - I., 1943-1948 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Illustrations., 1968-1973; About permission to use. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - India., 1916-1951 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Indian Agencies., 1917-1951 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Indiana Historical Society. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Indiana University Administration - Miscellaneous. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Indiana University - Botany Faculty., 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Indiana University - Insurance. T.I.A.A.: C.R.E.F. Annuities. (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Insurance Policies - Miscellaneous., 1938-1970; Includes Mortgages; car insurance policies; order forms for purchasing. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - International Botanical Congress., 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - International Society of Plant Morphologists., 1951-1969 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Invitation Papers., 1929-1939 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - J., 1943-1955 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Jansen, P., 1930-1946 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Japan., 1929-1932; About grasses. (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Just, Theodore. (University of Notre Dame)., 1934-1946 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - K-S, 73 Folders
    - K., 1941-1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Kew Botanic Garden., 1935-1950 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Kinsey, Alfred C. - American Midland., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Kudos., 1922-1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - L., 1937-1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Latin America., 1930-1945; Includes official papers; pamphlets, etc. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Laboratory Manual., 1958-1966; Includes bills & expense sheets, etc. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Linguistic Institute., 1948-1952 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - M., 1934-1957 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Macmillan - correspondence., About INDIAN CORN IN OLD AMERICA. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Maize Breeding., 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Maize Committee., 1949-1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Maize Genetics., 1939-1950 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Mangelsdorf, P.C., 1923-1953 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Medical Supply Co., 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Men of Science - Indiana., 1945-1950 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Mesa Verde., 1963; About corn growing. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Mexico., 1941-1948 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Miles, C. Donald., 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Miller, Isabel & Edwin C., 1935-1949 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Mottier, David M., 1920-1940 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - N., 1945-1955 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - New England Botanical Club., 1944-1946; Includes pamphlets, etc. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - O'Neal, Claude E., 1939-1971 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Orientation - Foreign Students., 1960-1962; Inclusive. (Box 3, Folder 25-27)
    - P., 1933-1960 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Page, Virginia., 1928-1971; Includes Graduate Student information. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Parodi, Lorenzo R., 1927-1951 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Payne, Fernandus., 1935-1947; Includes memos, etc. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Pendleton, Robert L., 1946-1957 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Peru., 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Phillippine Islands., 1917-1929; About grasses. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Photography - Miscellaneous., 1950-1964 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - PLANT BIOLOGY., 1941-1965; Includes reviews. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Plant Introduction - Plant Quarantine., 1944-1959; Includes forms, etc. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Pohl, Richard W. - Iowa State Univ., 1960-1971; About exchange of seeds and p1ants. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Popenoe, Wilson & John., 1934-1964 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Publications - Comments on., 1916-1964 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Publications - University of Chicago Press., 1922-1933 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - R., 1935-1961 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Radio., 1943-1948 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Randolph, Lowell F., 1947-1966 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Recommendations., 1955-1961 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Reed, Helen., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Reeder, John H., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Research - Reports on., 1934-1939 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Retirement Letters., 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Reviews., 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Riecken, William E., 1941-1950 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - Mexico., 1955-1964 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Rodriguez, Juan (Guatemala)., 1896-1917 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - S., 1937-1962 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Sabbatical., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - St. John, R.C. - DeKalb Agricultural Association., 1941-1951 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Sass, John E., 1936-1947 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - W.B. Saunders Co., Pub. - Botany text., 1938-1965; Includes statements, invoices, requests for permission to reproduce illustrations, etc. (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Schaffer, John H., 1920-1932 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Seed & Plant Introduction - U.S.D.A., 1916-1955 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Seed Trade Association., 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Seeds & Seed Plants., 1973; Includes article on seeds of plants. (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Sharman, B.C., 1938-1944 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Sigma XI., 1904-1968; Includes Bulletin on Constitution & By-Laws; a List of Officers, etc. (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Sohns, Ernest R., 1946-1956 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - South Africa., 1928-1957 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - South America., 1916-1938 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Soviet Union., 1935-1939 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Speaking Engagements., 1945-1952 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Sprague, G.F., 1953-1955; Includes galley proofs. (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Stevens, 0.A., 1945-1950; About Laboratory Manual. (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Summer Institute for Teachers., 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Swallen, Jason H., 1937-1950 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - T-Z, 42 Folders
    - T., 1922-1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Tax Receipts & Returns., 1939-1954 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - Taxonomy., 1952-1956; Includes papers of taxonomy. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Teachers' Training Committee., 1934-1944 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Teaching of botany., Includes outlines for teaching botany. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Television., 1955-1956; About I.U. Television series on botany. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Temporary File., 1938-1975; Includes miscellaneous correspondence. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Textbook., 1946-1959; Includes complimentary copies of articles. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Thailand Project., 1952-1970 (Box 4, Folder 10-13)
    - Thailand Project. A-Z. (Box 4, Folder 14-18)
    - Thailand. Class Records. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Thailand. Contract Activities., 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Thailand. Miscellaneous. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Thailand. Monthly Reports., 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Thailand. Wright, W.W. & Porter, W.P., 1955-1959; Includes programs, work­sheets, memos. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Torch Club., 1950-1953; Includes memos, membership lists, etc. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Union Starch & Refining Co., 1955-1958 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - U.S.D.A. - Miscellaneous., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - University Council., 1935-1941 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - University Presses., 1952-1953; About publishing INDIAN CORN IN OLD AMERICA. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - V., 1937-1953 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Valencia, Juan I., 1943-1945 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - VanFleet, Dick., 1939-1957 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Venezuela., 1942-1947 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Visiting Scientists Program., 1955-1960 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - W., 1943-1959 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Weigel, Oswald., 1930-1937; About rare books, grasses, etc. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Wells, Herman B., 1937-1962; Includes reports. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Whiting, Alfred F., 1940-1942 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Wylie, Robert B., 1919-1959 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Y., 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Young, R.A. - U.S.D.A., 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Z., 1934-1973 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Zeiner, Helen., 1943-1968 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Writings
  - Botany [textbook]. 3rd edition. Philadelphia, W.B. Saunders, 1956; Illustrations, photographs, drawings, etc. used in the above text as well as other texts by P.W.; page proof. (Box 5, Folder 1-9)
  - Charles C. Deam biography. Catalogue of the Deam library., Typescript, ditto, and carbon. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Charles C. Deam biography. Deamiana - contributed by W.A. Daily., Typescript, ditto, and carbon. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Contains correspondence of Charles Deam, Nov. 26, 1933 — Dec. 8, 1952.
  - Deam biography., A paste-up typescript; final draft typescript; carbon of first complete manuscript. 68p.; typescript of variant draft; carbon copies of various portions of biography. (Box 5, Folder 12-16)
  - Charles C. Deam biography., Photographs. (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
  - Charles C. Deam biography., Clippings. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Evolution of maize., Illustrations for P.W.'s dissertation, 1918. (Box 5, Folder 20-22)
  - How the corn plant went to Europe., 1st draft, 14 leaves; typescript, 19 leaves; 2 carbon copies, 12 leaves. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Liberal education., Paper written for a college English class, 1911. 3p. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - The morphology of grasses., Draft pages for unfinished book. (Box 5, Folder 25-32)
  - Translations (Box 5, Folder 25-32)
    - Grasses. Various articles on Morphology and Phylogeny, translated from the German, Paul Weatherwax, 1929., T.D. 206p. Bound. (Box 5, Folder 25-32)
    - Grasses. Articles on Morphology and Taxonomy, translated from French and German, Paul Weatherwax, 1936., T.D. 210p. Bound. (Box 5, Folder 25-32)
- Miscellaneous
  Scope and Contents
  Includes memorabilia, college class notes, trip diaries, etc.
  - Accession lists., Seeds (3 notebooks); grass seeds, exclusive of Zea (2 notebooks); grass seeds and living plants excluding Zea (1 notebook); lose pages. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - College notes, ca. 1915, for geology, evolution, physical chemistry, and physiological chemistry., 11 notebooks. (Box 6, Folder 2-7)
  - Memorabilia., Including information about passports; P.W.'s grade cards from I.U., etc. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Planting record, 1952-1963; 1 notebook. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - School books, 1911?; 2 notebooks (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Student Grade Book, 1911-1915 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Trip diaries, 1925-1957; 17 notebooks (Box 6, Folder 12-15)
  - Miscellaneous notes, Mar. 1934-Oct. 1940; May 1946-May 1951; 3 notebooks. (Box 6, Folder 16)